themediterraneandish.com 2019-05-07

# Policies and Disclosures | The Mediterranean Dish

[www.themediterraneandish.com](https://www.themediterraneandish.com/) (The Mediterranean Dish®) is property of The Mediterranean Dish, LLC

###  **Content Use Policy**

[www.themediterraneandish.com](https://www.themediterraneandish.com/) is a personal blog dedicated to modern Mediterranean cooking and the Mediterranean lifestyle. The blog is written by Suzy Karadsheh. Unless otherwise noted, all content and photography are © The Mediterranean Dish, LLC.  All rights reserved. Please do not reproduce any text or photographs without prior written consent from owner(s). For inquiries regarding the use of content or purchase of photographs seen here, please contact us via this [contact form.](https://www.themediterraneandish.com/contact-us/)

###  **Privacy Policy**

[www.themediterraneandish.com](https://www.themediterraneandish.com/) ( “The Mediterranean Dish” “website” “we” or “us” or “our”) respects the privacy of our users (“user” “reader” “visitor” or “you”). This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use, disclose, and safeguard your information when you visit our website including any other media form, media channel, mobile website, or mobile application related or connected thereto (collectively, the “Site”). Please read this Privacy Policy carefully.

 **Personal Data**

You may voluntarily share personally identifiable information, such as your name, address, email address, and telephone number, and demographic information, such as your age, gender, hometown, and interests when you choose to participate in various activities related to the Site, such as newsletter subscriptions, downloads, and website comments. You are under no obligation to provide us with personal information of any kind, however, your refusal to do so may prevent you from using certain features of the Site.

 **Log Files**

Like many other  websites, www.themediterrraneandish.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

 **Cookies and Web Beacons**

Cookies are very small text files that are stored on your computer when you visit some websites. Cookies are used by most websites to tailor content and marketing messages to better suit your needs. For example, cookies help us monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not so that we can provide content that is most helpful to you.

A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

If you prefer not to allow the use of cookies, you can change the configuration of your browser to warn you when you receive a cookie or automatically reject them. If you would like to find out more about cookies, you can visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)

 **Advertising**

We also use third party advertisements on [www.themediterraneandish.com](https://www.themediterraneandish.com/), these advertisements are a means to support the site and help us to continue to provide you with free useful content.

Advertisers such as AdThrive, Google, and other third party partners, may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site. The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by these advertisers is mainly for geotargeting purposes to serve advertisements that are most helpful and relevant to you. Advertisers may collect data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

 **For European Economic Area Residents**

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact AdThrive at [info@adthrive.com](mailto:info@adthrive.com). If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

 **Links to Other Sites**

Occasionally, we may link to other websites of interest (such as, when we publish a roundup of recipes including recipes from around the web.) Once you have used these links to leave our site, please note, we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

 **Comments**

When you share a comment on this blog, you agree to share your name, email address, website and IP address with us.  This information allows you to post a comment and it will not be used for any other purpose. Other than your name, the information will not be visible to others. Leaving a comment does not automatically subscribe you to our e-mail newsletter.

Your comment, or parts of it, may be shared through our media channels as testimony for the sake of encouraging other users. Only a first name may be used.

 **E-mail**

If you have chosen to subscribe to our large e-mail list, thank you! E-mail is the best way to remain in touch with The Mediterranean Dish. The information you voluntarily shared such as name and e-mail address are used so that we can provide our free cookbook, weekly recipes, meal plans, specials or promotions, and other information that may be helpful to you.

When you subscribe, you will be asked to confirm your subscription so that we can be sure you want to hear from us. If you change your mind at any point in time, you can certainly unsubscribe from the list; this option is available at the bottom of each e-mail you receive from us.

Our e-mail provider may also use cookies and other technologies to help track non-personal information that allows us to improve the quality of the content we send to you.

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we are required by law to do so.

 **When Might Information  be Disclosed? **

This is very rare, however, if we believe the release of information is necessary to respond to legal process, to investigate or remedy potential violations of our policies, or to protect the rights, property, and safety of others, we may share your information as permitted or required by any applicable law, rule, or regulation. This includes exchanging information with other entities for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

From time to time, we may share your information with third parties that perform services for us or on our behalf, including data analysis, email delivery, hosting services, customer service, and marketing assistance. This is only to help us improve our service to you.

###  **The Mediterranean Dish Store Policies**

As a service to our visitors and readers, we provide quality Mediterranean ingredients for purchase through [The Mediterranean Dish store.](https://www.themediterraneandish.com/store/) This is available to residents of the United States. We use secure checkout services in order for you to complete your purchase.

Your personal information such as name, e-mail address, physical address is used to process and ship your order. On occasion, you may receive an e-mail with information about new products, specials, or helpful information from the blog (such as how to use a certain ingredient).

 **What we collect and store**

While you visit our site, we’ll track:

  * Products you’ve viewed: we’ll use this to, for example, show you products you’ve recently viewed
  * Location, IP address and browser type: we’ll use this for purposes like estimating taxes and shipping
  * Shipping address: we’ll ask you to enter this so we can, for instance, estimate shipping before you place an order, and send you the order!

We’ll also use cookies to keep track of cart contents while you’re browsing our site.

When you purchase from us, we’ll ask you to provide information including your name, billing address, shipping address, email address, phone number, credit card/payment details and optional account information like username and password. We’ll use this information for purposes, such as, to:

  * Send you information about your account and order
  * Respond to your requests, including refunds and complaints
  * Process payments and prevent fraud
  * Set up your account for our store
  * Comply with any legal obligations we have, such as calculating taxes
  * Improve our store offerings
  * Send you marketing messages, if you choose to receive them

If you create an account, we will store your name, address, email and phone number, which will be used to populate the checkout for future orders.

We generally store information about you for as long as we need the information for the purposes for which we collect and use it, and we are not legally required to continue to keep it. This includes your name, email address and billing and shipping addresses.

We will also store comments or reviews, if you choose to leave them.

 **Who on our team has access**

Members of our team have access to the information you provide us. For example, both Administrators and Shop Managers can access:

  * Order information like what was purchased, when it was purchased and where it should be sent, and
  * Customer information like your name, email address, and billing and shipping information.

Our team members have access to this information to help fulfill orders, process refunds and support you.

 **What we share with others**

We share information with third parties who help us provide our orders and store services to you; for example —

 **Payments**

We accept payments through PayPal and Stripe. When processing payments, some of your data will be passed to PayPal or Stripe, including information required to process or support the payment, such as the purchase total and billing information.

Please see the [PayPal Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) for more details.

Please see the [Stripe Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/gb/privacy), for more details.

Our privacy policy above applies to information collected through the store as well as any other part of our site or media channels.

 **Store Return Policy**

When you place an order through [our store](https://www.themediterraneandish.com/store/), we take every measure to make sure the products arrive to you safely and in top shape. Should you, by any chance, receive a damaged shipment (ex. broken bottle of olive oil),  please reject the shipment and/or inform us via [admin@themediterraneandish.com](mailto:admin@themediterraneandish.com). We will track the original order and will do our best to replace it promptly. Otherwise, we are unable to accept returns.

###  **Nutritional Information Disclosure  **

Please read full[ nutrition disclosure.](https://www.themediterraneandish.com/nutrition-information-disclosure/)

This is a personal food blog, and the recipe creator(s), writer (s), and publisher (s) of themediterraneandish.com are not health professionals, nutritionists, or registered dietitians. As a service to our users, we have recently opted to provide nutritional information. Please note, this information is our very best estimate. This website is not intended as nutritional advice and readers of this website are ultimately responsible for all decisions pertaining to their health. Readers assume full responsibility for consulting a qualified health professional regarding health conditions or concerns before starting a new health program or diet.

The Mediterranean Dish expressly disclaims any and all liability of any kind with respect to any act or omission wholly or in part in reliance on anything contained in this website.

###  **Additional Disclosures**

This blog abides by word of mouth marketing standards. We believe in honesty of relationship, opinion and identity. The occasional compensation received may influence the advertising content, topics or posts made in this blog, but will _not_ affect the opinions expressed.  We will only recommend products that we truly believe in and love. That content, advertising space or post will be clearly identified as paid or sponsored content.

[www.themediterraneandish.com](https://www.themediterraneandish.com/) is a participant in some affiliate programs including the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites. Should you make a purchase through one of the links shared here, there will be no added cost to you whatsoever.

The owner(s) of this blog is occasionally compensated to provide opinion on products, services, websites and various other topics. Even though the owner(s) of this blog receives compensation for our posts or advertisements on an occasional basis, we always give our honest opinions, findings, beliefs, or experiences on those topics or products. The views and opinions expressed on this blog are purely the bloggers’ own. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question.

This blog does not contain any content which might present a conflict of interest.

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time and for any reason. We will alert you about any changes by updating the “Revised” date of this Privacy Policy. Any changes or modifications will be effective immediately upon posting the updated Privacy Policy on the Site, and you waive the right to receive specific notice of each such change or modification. You are encouraged to periodically review this Privacy Policy to stay informed of updates. You will be deemed to have been made aware of, will be subject to, and will be deemed to have accepted the changes in any revised Privacy Policy by your continued use of the Site after the date such revised Privacy Policy is posted.

Policies and Disclosures last updated May 23, 2018.
